There once lived a tiger which believed that he was the most powerful animal on the mountain.
He strolled haughtily, boasting about his great strength, and said,
“I’m the king of all the animals on the mountain. Nothing scares me!”
It was true!
He was scary. And when the other animals heard his roaring,
they let out a shriek of fear and ran away in a hurry.
One very cold winter, the Tiger could not hunt for food for many days because of the heavy snow.
“I’m starving to death. I can’t stand it any longer. I should go into town to get something to eat.”
The Tiger was lying down at the foot of the mountain, waiting until it got dark.
He found a farmhouse with a barn. There was a cow sleeping inside, snoring loudly.
“A-ha! A cow! That’s a perfect dinner!”
The Tiger licked his chops at the cow.
Just then, the Tiger heard a small child crying from inside the house.
“Waa! Waa!”
“Stop crying or the monster will get you,” said his mother.
“Waa! Waa!” the child continued to cry, even though his mother tried to comfort him.
“Shh! There’s a tiger outside. Stop crying, or he’ll come and get you.”
The Tiger was suddenly frightened.
“How can she know where I am now? I must be more careful.”
“Waa! Waa!” The child didn’t stop crying, in fact, he cried even louder.
“Hum, why isn’t he afraid of me?”
“Please stop crying! I have a dried persimmon for you.”
Surprisingly, when his mother told him about the dried persimmon, the child immediately stopped crying.
“What is a dried persimmon?” thought the Tiger.
“It must be a very scary beast. Is it really here? I must be careful.”
The Tiger walked very carefully and quietly back to the barn.
At that moment, a large, black figure crept through the barn door.
“Eek! It must be the dried persimmon.”
The Tiger was too scared to move.
The black figure walked to the Tiger and rubbed its back.
“Oh, this one’s really nice and fat! I like it.”
The large, black figure was really a thief who had come to steal the farmer's cow.
Because it was dark, the Thief thought that the furry Tiger was really a cow.
When the Thief pulled the Tiger out of the barn by his tail, he suddenly trembled with fear.
“Oh no! This isn’t a cow at all. It’s a Tiger! Now I’ll die for sure,” the Thief thought to himself.
“Oh no! The dried persimmon has me by my tail. I’ll die for sure,” the Tiger thought to himself.
Both the Tiger and the Thief were too afraid to move at all.
“I can’t die like this. I’ll run for my life.”
When the Tiger started to run, the Thief thought the Tiger was trying to eat him.
So he immediately jumped on the Tiger’s back and held onto the Tiger's body.
The scared Tiger bucked up and down, but the Thief held on to it even tighter.
The Tiger continued running and running through the mountain.
As the Tiger passed under a tree, the Thief successfully grabbed a branch and didn’t let go.
The Tiger kept running, never looking back.
The Tiger finally realized that there was nothing on his back after many miles of running.
“That was too close! I was almost eaten by the dried persimmon. I was so lucky today.”
Since that day, the frightened Tiger never went to the town again for fear of the super-scary dried persimmon.